Indiana University Provost records, 1891-1929 C173
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University Provost records
1891-1929
1924-1928
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University. Provost
C173
2 cubic feet
The University Provost position was created by William Lowe Bryan in 1923 in order to delegate management of the Indianapolis campus to another administrator. Samuel E. Smith held this position until his death in 1928. Collection consists of records of the University Provost in two series: Correspondence and Subject files. The Correspondence series is further organized in three subseries: General, State field nursing, and Construction. The Subject files series contains inventories, records, and reports from a variety of sources. The subject of medicine is most prominent and a good number of the records are about Riley Hospital for Children. Copies of several House Bills can also be found here.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Advance notice required.
Administrative History
In 1923, President Bryan created the position of provost to relieve him of the increasing amount of administrative detail connected to Indiana University's Indianapolis campus. He appointed Samuel E. Smith to the post, who remained in this position until his death in 1928. During his time as provost, Smith oversaw the expanding medical and extension centers in Indianapolis, in addition to the construction of the 10th Street Memorial Stadium on the Bloomington campus.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the provost are divided into two series: Correspondence and Subject files. The correspondence series is further divided into three subseries: general, state field nursing, and construction.
The general correspondence is made up of a variety of subjects Smith addressed in his position as provost. The state field nursing subseries consists of correspondence and reports on the State Field Nursing project sponsored jointly by the Indiana University Training School for Nurses, the Extension Division, and the James Whitcomb Riley Memorial Hospital. The goal of this project was to extend the services of the Riley Hospital to communities throughout Indiana. The subseries on construction includes correspondence about construction throughout IU's Bloomington and Indianapolis campuses, but primarily consists of correspondence on the construction of the 10th Street Memorial Stadium.
The Subject files series contains inventories, records, and reports from a variety of sources. The subject of medicine is most prominent and a good number of the records are about Riley Hospital for Children. Copies of several House Bills can also be found here.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into two series, Correspondence and Subject files.
Acquisition Information
Accn. 0080
University extension --Indiana --Indianapolis --History --20th century --Sources.; Medical centers --Indiana --Indianapolis --Design and construction --History --20th century --Sources.; Indiana University. Indianapolis Center -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Memorial Stadium (1925-1982) (Bloomington, Ind.); Indiana University -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Indiana University. Indianapolis Center -- Archives; Indiana University. Indianapolis Center -- Records and correspondence; Indiana University. Indianapolis Center -- Buildings -- Design and construction -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Riley Hospital -- Records and correspondence; Indiana University -- Buildings -- Design and construction -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; Indiana University. Provost -- Archives; Indiana University. Provost -- Records and correspondence; Smith, Samuel E., 1861-1928 -- Archives; Smith, Samuel E., 1861-1928 -- Correspondence
- Correspondence, 1923-1928
  - General, 1923-1928
    - Correspondence (Box 1)
      - 1923 (Box 1)
      - A - B, 1924 (Box 1)
      - C - D, 1924 (Box 1)
      - E - F, 1924 (Box 1)
      - G - L, 1924 (Box 1)
      - M - R, 1924 (Box 1)
      - S - Z, 1924 (Box 1)
      - A - C, 1925 (Box 1)
      - C - D, 1925 (Box 1)
      - E - F, 1925 (Box 1)
      - G - L, 1925 (Box 1)
      - M - N, 1925 (Box 1)
      - O - R, 1925 (Box 1)
      - S, 1925 (Box 1)
      - S-W, 1925 (Box 1)
      - A - B, 1926 (Box 1)
      - C - D, 1926 (Box 1)
      - E - F, 1926 (Box 1)
      - G - J, 1926 (Box 1)
      - K - O, 1926 (Box 1)
      - P - R, 1926 (Box 1)
      - S, 1926 (Box 1)
      - S - V, 1926 (Box 1)
      - A - C, 1927 (Box 1)
      - D - F, 1927 (Box 1)
      - G - M, 1927 (Box 2)
      - N - R, 1927 (Box 2)
      - S (Box 2)
        - 1927 (Box 2)
        - 1927 (Box 2)
        - 1927 (Box 2)
      - T - W, 1927 (Box 2)
      - A - T, 1928 (Box 2)
  - State Field Nursing, 1924-1928
    - Relating to state field nursing (Box 2)
      - purpose / general statements, Undated (Box 2)
      - nurses reports (Box 2)
        - 1924-1928 (Box 2)
        - 1924-1928 (Box 2)
        - 1924-1928 (Box 2)
        - 1924-1928 (Box 2)
      - Riley Hospital Service Committee, Undated (Box 2)
  - Construction, 1924-1928
    - Relating to construction (Box 2)
      - A - D (Box 2)
        - 1924-1928 (Box 2)
        - 1924-1928 (Box 2)
      - E - I, 1924-1928 (Box 2)
      - J - R, 1924-1928 (Box 2)
      - J - R, 1924-1928 (Box 2)
    - Stadium (Box 2)
      - A - G, 1924-1928 (Box 2)
      - H - M, 1924-1928 (Box 2)
      - N - R, 1924-1928 (Box 2)
      - S, 1924-1928 (Box 2)
      - T - Y, 1924-1928 (Box 2)
- Subject files, 1891-1929
  - Arbutus, Undated (Box 2)
  - Dentistry, School of, 1923 - 1929 (Box 2)
  - Financial Status - IU-Bloomington & Indianapolis extension center, 1900 - 1926 (Box 2)
  - Indiana State Government, 1891 - 1925 (Box 2)
  - Insurance, Undated (Box 2)
  - Inventory, Subject files, Undated (Box 2)
  - Riley Hospital, Robert W. Long Hospital, & Indianapolis Medical Center, 1918-1926 (Box 2)